In this video, I'm going to be talking to you about
这一视频将介绍 Sass
Sass and why it's such an awesome front-end tool.
以及为什么 Sass 是一个出色的前端工具
The documentation calls itself a CSS extension language.
官方文档称自己是 CSS 的扩展语言
That can be a little bit confusing,
这句话可能会让人有些困惑
but really what Sass is,
Sass 到底是什么?
is this awesome collection of extra syntax for CSS that will help you write better,
Sass 实际上是出色的 CSS 扩展语法集合 能帮助你编写更好
more concrete and efficient styles.
更清晰和高效的样式
So this is a really important thing to learn,
这是非常值得学习的
mostly because it's a really common tool in front-end development.
主要也因为它是前端开发中很常用的工具
At some point in your interviewing,
在某些面试中
you'll come across questions about Sass,
你可能会遇到关于 Sass 的问题
and I can guarantee you you'll come across Sass style sheets at some point.
并且我敢保证你肯定会在某些时候遇到 Sass 样式表
So they're really handy to learn.
所以学习这一工具会很方便
It's a really powerful way to write better CSS syntax.
这真的是编写更好 CSS 语法的强力工具
So let's talk about why we need Webpack in order to run CSS and Sass.
接下来讨论一下 为什么需要 webpack 来运行 CSS 和 Sass?
We know that we've already used CSS on our browsers before and we never needed Webpack.
我们知道自己在浏览器上使用过 CSS 并不需要 webpack
So the question is,
所以问题是
what's so different about Sass that now we need Webpack in order to run our styles?
Sass 有何不同 以至于需要 webpack 来运行样式?
It might seem a little bit strange until we realize
这似乎有点奇怪 除非我们认识到
the structure of how the Internet works with our styles in our HTML.
因特网处理 HTML 中样式的原理
We always start with the client.
我们总是从客户端启动
On the client or browser,
在客户端或浏览器上
we can run HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
可以运行 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript
But when our client makes a request to our server,
但是当客户端向服务器发出请求时
if our server has Sass instead of CSS,
如果服务器使用 Sass 而不是 CSS
it's going to try and send that Sass to the client,
它会尝试将 Sass 发送给客户端
but the browser doesn't know what Sass is,
但是浏览器不知道 Sass 是什么
we cannot have any Sass on this side of our application.
应用的这一端不能出现任何 Sass
So when we're over here on the server,
因此 当我们在服务端时
we can use Webpack to take the really awesome Sass files that we
可以使用 webpack 来处理 Sass 文件
make and turn them into CSS so that we can send the CSS back to the client.
将其转换为 CSS 这样就可以将 CSS 发送给客户端
That whole process is a really important thing to understand that whenever you're
理解整个过程是很重要的
using a pre-processed CSS library like less or Sass,
每当使用像 less 或 Sass 这样的 CSS 预处理库时
they're really common in front-end development,
它们在前端开发中真的很常用
but you always need a build step.
你都始终需要构建步骤
This is one of the major reasons that we even use build tools,
这也是我们使用构建工具的主要原因之一
Grunt and Gulp and Webpack are all really common for turning
Grunt、Gulp 和 webpack 都是很常见的
your Sass into CSS on the server side so that you can send it to the client.
可以在服务端将 Sass 转换为 CSS 然后再发送到客户端的构建工具